# CRAIG BENNETT

Jonesborough, TN 37659 | Phone:423.524.0127 | Email: <a href="mailto:craig.bennett5117@gmail.com">craig.bennett5117@gmail.com</a>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Craig5117">https://github.com/Craig5117</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://craigbennett-reaction.herokuapp.com/">https://github.com/Craig5117</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://craigbennett-reaction.herokuapp.com/">https://craigbennett-reaction.herokuapp.com/</a> | LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigbennett5117/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/craigbennett5117/</a>

#### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full stack developer with experience working with React and C#. I am skilled in React, HTML, CSS (Bootstrap, Bulma, Material-UI), JavaScript, jQuery, GraphQL API, and RESTful API architecture. I also have experience working with Wordpress/PHP, C#/ASP.NET, TypeScript, and Angular. Prior to my career in development, I spent several years leading translation teams in the South Pacific. I am a great team player, and I am skilled at team building and team leadership as well. I am a tenaciously hard worker, a fast learner, and an excellent problem solver. I am ready to apply my skills and tenacity to meet your development needs.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: React, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, PHP, C#

Database: MySQL 8, MongoDB, Prisma, GraphQL

Other: Heroku, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap, Material-UI, node.js, RESTful API, Redux, WordPress, ASP.NET

# **PROJECTS**

SecureMoneyMasters - securemoneymasters.com | https://github.com/Craig5117/secure-money-masters

Custom Wordpress theme designed for the landing site of SecureMoneyMastes, a financial advising firm in Bristol, TN

- Handwritten CSS
- Built using WordPress/PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Custom plugins for custom Gutenberg block types to fit the clients needs

Katy's ToyBox - Repo: <a href="https://github.com/Craig5117/katys-toybox">https://github.com/Craig5117/katys-toybox</a>

 $Demo: \underline{https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pjV5m76pWOr4zTMTHv55dpoXEdF8FF7x/view?usp=sharing} \\$ 

An inventory management system built for an online toy business.

- Fully designed API from the ground up using Prisma, MySQL, and Apollo GraphQL
- Lightning fast UI built with NextJS, React, and Material-UI
- Utilizes CSS modules

**SLP Goalden** - mighty-falls-97052.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/Craig5117/slp-goalden

Full-stack app that is designed to assist speech language pathologists in storing tracking student language goal data and progress

- Designed project architecture front-end and back-end.
- Wrote all of the logic that connects the front-end UI to the back-end routes and database.
- Tools used: node.js, MySQL, Sequelize Express, express-session, Materialize, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3

CritterTails - <a href="https://crittertails.herokuapp.com/">https://crittertails.herokuapp.com/</a> | <a href

A social media app for pet lovers to post as their pets.

- Built with React, Redux, and GraphQL
- Personally wrote the ReactJS components and hooks, all Redux logic, all front end GraphQL logic
- Tools used: React, Apollo GraphQL, Redux, React-Bootstrap, node.js, Express, Cloudinary

#### EXPERIENCE

**Native Technical Solutions Junior Software Developer**  Oklahoma City, OK July 2021 – Present

Worked on an app for a client in the HealthCare industry. Responsibilities included making improvements to the app, debugging, and converting parts of the older Angular 1 front end to React.

Working with React, Angular, C#, ASP.NET, MongoDB, Material-UI, and Bootstrap. Daily tasks involve designing React components, styling using Material-UI, and writing back-end methods in ASP.NET framework to access the MongoDB API. Project features MVC architecture. Other occasional tasks involve updating and troubleshooting Angular portions of the app.

### Freelance Web Developer

Johnson City, TN May 2021 - Present

Developing and optimizing web solutions in the Johnson City-Bristol-Kingsport area. Using technologies such as Javascript, React, MySQL, Prisma, NextJS, Node, PHP and WordPress.

### Projects:

SecureMoneyMasters

A landing site for a financial advising firm located in Bristol, TN. Built as a custom WordPress theme using PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.

• Katy's ToyBox

An inventory management system for an online toy business. Built with Prisma, MySQL, GraphQL, NextJS, and Material-UI.

# **Pioneer Bible Translators Language Affairs Coordinator**

Vanuatu 2016 - 2021

**KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** 

- Worked with 4 teams from 4 different languages
- Helped each team develop their own specific strategies to meet their translation project goals
- Wrote policies outlining standards for acceptable work and consequences for not reaching goals or absences from team events

# **Pioneer Bible Translators** IT Repair Technician

Vanuatu 2014 - 2021

**KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:** 

• Maintained and worked on over 20 computers: small hardware repairs, updating and maintaining antivirus and other software to synchronize with organizational policies and licenses.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bootcamp Certificate in Full Stack Web Development** Vanderbilt University – Nashville, TN

Graduated with a 4.0 GPA (99.83).

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, node.js, SQL Databases, MongoDB, GraphQL, React, Redux, & MERN.

# **Graduate Certificate in Applied Linguistics** Dallas International University – Dallas, TX

Graduated with a 4.0 GPA. A 2 year program focused on linguistic analysis with courses on phonetics, phonology, grammar, semantics, and translation.

#### M.A. Biblical Languages Lincoln Christian University – Lincoln, IL

Graduated with a 4.0 GPA.

### **B.A. Biblical Studies**

Johnson University - Knoxville, TN

Graduated Summa Cum Laude with a 3.9 GPA.